Pranav Panchal

DATA ANALYST

- pranavpanchal303@gmail.com
- 226-340-9685
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/pranavpanchal303
- github.com/ppanchal303

PROFILE

I have 7 years of product design experience and I am a recent Data Science graduate seeking a career change into the data domain. I find working with data and implementing complex ideas and systems to be enjoyable. My hobby of coding has further fueled my intrigue in the field of data science.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Data Science

JUL 2022 - OCT 2022, ONTARIO, CANADA

University of Windsor | Master of Engineering, Mechanical

SEP 2019 - DEC 2020, WINDSOR, CANADA

University of Mumbai | Bachelor of Engineering, Mechanical

JUN 2009 - MAY 2013, MUMBAI, INDIA

SKILLS

- SQL
- Pvthon
- Critical Thinking
- Tableau
- Data Visualization
- Problem Solving
- Git Bash
- Hypothesis Testing
- Team Player

DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

Olympic Data Exploration | Exploratory Data Analysis

FEB 2023 - FEB 2023, Personal Project

- Conducted EDA using MySQL on Olympic data set containing over 270K rows.
- Demonstrated efficient queries by employing sub-queries, views, joins etc. to extract precise information for data.

Audio Classification Project | Machine Learning Project

FEB 2023 - FEB 2023, Personal Project

- Actively engaged in working with unstructured audio data to advance understanding of the audio domain.
- Applying feature extraction techniques to unstructured audio files to classify them.

Snake Game | Machine Learning Capstone Project

AUG 2022 - OCT 2022, Data Science Capstone Project, BrainStation

- Developed a custom game environment from scratch and utilized Q learning technique to train the agent to explore and exploit the environment.
- Demonstrated the agent's adaptability and ability to achieve its objective even when the environment was modified.

Off The Court, WNBA | Industry Project

SEPT 2022, Data Science, BrainStation

- Collaborated with a cross-functional team of UX designers, web developers, and digital marketers in a hackathon to develop recommendations for increasing fan engagement in the WNBA.
- Conducted data scraping, priming, trend identification, and statistical analysis to generate actionable insights for the front-end team.

Mean, Median & Mode Imputation | Academic Project

MAY 2020 - AUG 2020, Data Mining, University of Windsor

 Proficiently applied 3M imputation method using MATLAB to impute missing values in 1144 incomplete datasets, encompassing both numeric and categorical data.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Product Development Engineer | MillerKnoll

JUN 2021 - JUN 2022, NORTH YORK, ON, CANADA

- Spearheaded the product design team.
- Designed and tested prototypes, analyzed results to validate designs and predict product performance.
- Managed engineering data using PTC Windchill to optimize data analysis, monitoring, and control.
- Successfully implemented Power BI to semi-automate data export from Windchill.

Deputy Manager | Godrej & Boyce Mfg. Co. Ltd.

AUG 2013 - AUG 2019, MUMBAI, INDIA

- Strategized and executed engineering activities in collaboration with crossfunctional teams.
- Successfully reduced product launch lead times by nearly 40% and prototyping costs by 25%.
- Mentored and coached junior team members and interns on design philosophy, manufacturing constraints, processes, collaboration, and overall business acumen.